;[
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments',
    question: 'Static posture',
    answer:
      'The positioning of the musculoskeletal system while the body is motionless.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Dynamic posture',
    answer: 'Alignment of the body while in motion.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Optimal movement',
    answer:
      'Moving in a biomechanically efficient manner that maximizes muscle recruitment and minimizes risk of injury.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Movement impairments',
    answer:
      'Abnormal movement patterns that can indicate possible muscle imbalances or mobility limitation.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Movement assessment',
    answer:
      'An assessment of a client’s movement patterns and postural alignment during movement or activity; also known as a dynamic postural assessment.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Muscle imbalance',
    answer:
      'When muscles on each side of a joint have altered length-tension relationships.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Mobility',
    answer:
      'Optimal flexibility and joint range of motion; ability to move freely.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Performance assessment',
    answer:
      'Assessments used to measure overall strength, muscular endurance, power, and agility.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Pes planus',
    answer: 'Collapsed arch of the foot; also known as flat feet.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Overactive',
    answer:
      'When elevated neural drive causes a muscle to be held in a chronic state of contraction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Underactive',
    answer:
      'When a muscle is experiencing neural inhibition and limited neuromuscular recruitment.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Static postural assessment',
    answer:
      'An assessment that provides insight to deviations from optimal alignment of the body in a standing posture.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Anterior',
    answer: 'On the front of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Posterior',
    answer: 'On the back of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Kinetic chain checkpoints',
    answer:
      'The five areas of the body that are monitored during movement assessments and exercise: foot/ankle, knees, lumbo-pelvic-hip complex, shoulders, and head.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Anterior pelvic tilt',
    answer:
      'An excessive forward rotation of the pelvis that results in greater lumbar lordosis.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Knee valgus',
    answer:
      'Knees collapse inward (knock knees) due to hip adduction and internal rotation; also known as medial knee displacement and genu valgum.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Knee varus',
    answer: 'Knees bow outward (bowlegged); also known as genu varum.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Pes planus distortion syndrome',
    answer:
      'Postural syndrome characterized by flat feet, knee valgus, and adducted and internally rotated hips.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Lower crossed syndrome',
    answer:
      'Postural syndrome characterized by anterior pelvic tilt and excessive lordosis of the lumbar spine.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Lordotic/Lordosis',
    answer:
      'The normal curvature of the cervical and lumbar spine regions, creating a concave portion of the spine.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Upper crossed syndrome',
    answer:
      'Postural syndrome characterized by a forward head and protracted shoulders.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Obesity',
    answer:
      'A complex disease involving an excessive amount of body fat; classified by a body mass index of 30 or greater.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Kinesiology',
    answer: 'Study of movement as it relates to anatomy and physiology.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Evidence-based practice',
    answer:
      'A practice that relies on evidence for guidance and decision-making and includes developing individual expertise, staying current on the best sources of external evidence (e.g., peer-reviewed research), and prioritizing client values and expectations.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Musculoskeletal system',
    answer:
      'The combined, interworking system of all muscles and bones in the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Deconditioned',
    answer:
      'A state of lost physical fitness, which may include muscle imbalances, decreased flexibility, and a lack of core and joint stability.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Overweight',
    answer:
      'A body weight greater than what is considered within normal standards; a body mass index of 25.0 to 29.9.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Joint stability',
    answer:
      'The support provided by tissues surrounding a joint to maintain and provide control during movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Socioeconomic status',
    answer:
      'The social standing of a person or group that includes education, income, and occupation.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Morbidity',
    answer: 'The state of having a disease.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Mortality',
    answer: 'A state or a risk of death or dying.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Homeostasis',
    answer:
      'The process by which the human body strives to maintain a relatively stable equilibrium.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Risk factor',
    answer:
      'Any attribute, characteristic, or exposure of an individual that increases the likelihood of developing a disease or injury.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Cholesterol',
    answer: 'A waxy, fatlike substance found in bodily cells.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Stroke',
    answer:
      'A sudden lack of blood supply to the brain, caused by either a blockage in an artery or ruptured blood vessel.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Heart attack',
    answer:
      'The action that occurs when an artery supplying the heart with blood and oxygen becomes blocked; medically known as a myocardial infarction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Heart failure',
    answer:
      'A condition in which the heart can’t pump enough blood to meet the body’s needs.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Heart valve problem',
    answer:
      'A condition that occurs when one or more heart valves do not function properly, causing shortness of breath and reduced oxygen supply to the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Arrhythmia',
    answer:
      'A problem with the rate or rhythm of a person’s heartbeat. The heart beats too quickly, too slowly, or with an irregular pattern.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Ischemic heart disease',
    answer:
      'A category of heart-related problems caused by the narrowing of coronary arteries, which supply blood and oxygen to the heart muscle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Atherosclerosis',
    answer:
      'The processes by which plaque is formed in arteries leading to reduced blood flow.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Physical activity',
    answer:
      'Bodily movement that results in energy expenditure and encompasses many modes and intensities. Movement that is not structured exercise such as recreational pursuits (e.g., golfing, gardening, and walking a dog).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Hypertension',
    answer: 'Consistently elevated blood pressure.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Systolic blood pressure (SBP)',
    answer:
      'The pressure in arteries and other blood vessels when the heart is contracting; the first (top) number recorded.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Diastolic blood  pressure (DBP)',
    answer:
      'The pressure in arteries and other blood vessels when heart is at rest or between beats; the second (bottom) number recorded.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Diabetes',
    answer:
      'Chronic metabolic disorder, caused by insulin deficiency, which impairs carbohydrate usage and enhances usage of fat and protein.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Glucose',
    answer: 'The simplest form of carbohydrate used by the body for energy.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Insulin resistance',
    answer:
      'The inability of the cells to respond to insulin; occurs in type 2 diabetes.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Cancer',
    answer:
      'A group of diseases involving abnormal cell growth with the potential to invade or spread to other parts of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)',
    answer:
      'A general term used to describe progressive lung diseases, including emphysema, chronic bronchitis, and refractory (nonreversible) asthma.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Endorphins',
    answer:
      'A group of hormones secreted by the brain that provides a variety of physiological functions, such as reducing the perception of pain.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Skeletal muscle',
    answer:
      'The type of muscle tissue that connects to bones and generates the forces that create movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Sprain',
    answer: 'A stretching or tearing of ligaments.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Plantar fasciitis',
    answer:
      'An inflammation of the fibrous tissue (plantar fascia) along the bottom of the foot, which often results in intense heel pain.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Patellar tendonitis',
    answer:
      'An injury or inflammation of the tendon that connects the patella (kneecap) to the tibia (shin bone).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Anterior  cruciate  ligament (ACL) tear',
    answer:
      'A stretch, partial tear, or complete tear of the anterior cruciate ligament of the knee.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Medial collateral ligament (MCL) tear',
    answer:
      'A stretch, partial tear, or complete tear of the medial collateral ligament of the knee.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 1',
    topic: 'The Modern State of Health and Fitness',
    question: 'Shoulder impingement syndrome',
    answer:
      'Shoulder pain caused by rotator cuff tissues rubbing against the acromion bone of the shoulder.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'Operational costs',
    answer:
      'The various monetary requirements associated with the day-to-day running of a business.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'High-intensity interval training (HIIT)',
    answer:
      'An exercise training method defined by intervals of near-maximal intensity broken up by relatively short rest periods.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'Adherence',
    answer: 'The level of commitment to a behavior or plan of action.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'Prospect',
    answer: 'An individual who has been identified as a potential client.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'Sales process',
    answer:
      'A system for learning about the needs of a potential client to be able to identify and present a number of solutions for those needs.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'Open-ended questions',
    answer:
      'Nondirective questions that can’t be answered with a simple yes or no answer; they require critical thinking to formulate a response.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'Working the ﬂoor',
    answer:
      'A rapport-building technique where fitness professionals walk around the gym floor talking to members without overtly presenting a sale.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'Rapport',
    answer:
      'A relationship in which two people understand each other’s ideas, have respect for one another, and communicate well.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'Forecasting',
    answer:
      'A business management technique that helps predict how much work is needed to meet a revenue goal.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'Unique selling proposition (USP)',
    answer:
      'Highlighting unique skills or traits during a sales presentation that allow an individual to stand out from the competition.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'Brand',
    answer:
      'A product or service identified by specific, unique characteristics.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 2',
    topic: 'The Personal Training Profession',
    question: 'SWOT analysis',
    answer:
      'A professional development technique that helps individuals identify their personal strengths and weaknesses, opportunities for growth, and potential threats to success.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Extrinsic motivation',
    answer:
      'When someone participates in an activity or behavior for some type of reward or recognition from others.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Intrinsic motivation',
    answer:
      'When people engage in an activity or behavior because they feel a sense of satisfaction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Outcome goals',
    answer: 'Goals focused on the end result.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Process goals',
    answer: 'Refers to the process of goal pursuit.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Social support',
    answer:
      'The intentional ways that people assist others in achieving a specific behavior.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Social physique anxiety',
    answer:
      'A specific form of anxiety that occurs in individuals who perceive that others could be negatively evaluating their physique.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Ambivalence',
    answer: 'Describes a person’s state of mixed feelings about a situation.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Instrumental support',
    answer:
      'The actions that directly facilitate a behavior to happen. In the context of exercise, instrumental support can include driving a person to a health club or paying for the gym membership.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Emotional support',
    answer:
      'The encouragement and positive reinforcement that is provided from an individual to another, which includes being caring, empathetic, and showing concern.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Empathy',
    answer:
      'The ability to identify with another person’s feelings, attitudes, or thoughts.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Informational support',
    answer: 'Providing accurate, current, and informative information.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Companionship support',
    answer:
      'When someone engages in a behavior with an individual. This type of support is often observed in an exercise setting where people exercise with a friend or partner.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Self-esteem',
    answer:
      'The way someone evaluates their own self-worth physically, emotionally, and socially.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Body image',
    answer:
      'The way someone views their physical self or visualizes their body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 3',
    topic: 'Psychology of Exercise',
    question: 'Sleep apnea',
    answer:
      'A sleep disorder in which a person’s breathing repeatedly stops and starts, which disrupts the body’s natural sleep cycle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Autonomy',
    answer: 'Acting in accordance with how one wants to behave.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Third space',
    answer:
      'A communal space, separate from home or work, where the client experiences their own sense of identity and relationship to others.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Behavior change techniques (BCTs)',
    answer:
      'Client interventions that are used to change some determinant of behavior.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Self-efficacy',
    answer:
      'One’s belief that they can complete a task, goal, or performance; also known as self-confidence.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Self-monitoring',
    answer:
      'Observing, measuring, and evaluating one’s own behavior, often in the form of a diary or log.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Determinants of behavior',
    answer:
      'Refers to the psychological, social, or environmental factors that influence behavior.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Intention',
    answer:
      'A construct that captures motivational factors that influence behavior. It indicates how hard people are willing to try and how much effort they are planning to exert.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Self-determination theory',
    answer: 'A broad theoretical framework for the study of human motivation.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Autonomous motivation',
    answer:
      'When motives for exercise relate to valuing the outcome, when exercise is consistent with the client’s identity, or when the client enjoys exercise.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Planning',
    answer: 'A concrete representation of when and where exercise will occur.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Attitudes',
    answer:
      'The degree to which a person has a favorable or unfavorable evaluation of the behavior of interest.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Outcome expectations',
    answer: 'The expected positive and negative consequences of a behavior.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Stress',
    answer:
      'The state of mental or emotional tension from demanding circumstances.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Perceived behavioral control',
    answer:
      'An evaluation of whether one has the means, resources, and opportunities to perform a behavior.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Affective judgment',
    answer: 'Referring to expected pleasure or enjoyment.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Subjective norms',
    answer:
      'Belief that an important person or group of people will approve and support a behavior.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Precontemplation',
    answer:
      'Client does not exercise and is not planning to start exercising within 6 months.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Contemplation',
    answer:
      'When a person is thinking about implementing change but has not yet taken any steps to get started; an individual may take action within the next 6 months.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Preparation',
    answer:
      'The client intends to act in the near future, usually within the next month.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Action',
    answer:
      'The client has made specific modifications in their exercise routine within the past 6 months.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Maintenance',
    answer:
      'The client has been exercising for more than 6 months and is working to prevent relapse.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Decisional balance',
    answer: 'Reflects the clients’ weighing of the pros and cons of changing.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Reflective listening',
    answer:
      'The process of seeking to understand the meaning of the speaker’s words and restating the idea back to the speaker to confirm that they were understood correctly.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Active listening',
    answer:
      'Listening style that involves having genuine interest in what the speaker is saying; requires the listener to fully concentrate to understand the speaker’s message.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Closed-ended questions',
    answer:
      'Directive questions that can be answered with one word, typically a yes or no.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Collecting summaries',
    answer:
      'Short sentences that continue the client’s thoughts and add momentum to the conversation.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Linking summaries',
    answer:
      'Summaries that tie together information the client has presented, perhaps even from previous sessions.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Transitional summaries',
    answer: 'Summaries used to wrap up a session or announce a shift in focus.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Affirmations',
    answer: 'Positive statements about character strengths.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Motivational interviewing',
    answer:
      'Client-centered, directive method for enhancing intrinsic motivation to change by exploring and resolving ambivalence.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Self-discrepancy',
    answer:
      'An internal conflict that occurs when an individual compares their actual self with their ideal self.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Sustain talk',
    answer: 'Talk that represents and predicts movement away from change.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Change talk',
    answer: 'Talk that reflects movement of the person toward behavior change.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: ' Implementation intentions',
    answer:
      'A behavior change technique that links a goal-directed response to situational cues by specifying when, where, and how to act.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Coping plans',
    answer:
      'A behavior change technique that involves anticipating barriers to goal action and proactively preparing strategies that prioritize intentional behavior over counterproductive habitual responses.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Self-talk',
    answer:
      'Internal dialogue in which the individual interprets feelings and perceptions, regulates and changes evaluations and convictions, and gives himself or herself instructions and reinforcement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Reverse listing',
    answer: 'Replacing negative statements with positive statements.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Stopping',
    answer: 'The act of saying “stop” out loud to undesired statements.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Cognitive fusion',
    answer: 'When people believe the exact content of their own thoughts.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Imagery',
    answer: 'The process created to produce internalized experiences.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Appearance imagery',
    answer: 'When a person imagines appearance or healthrelated outcomes.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Energy imagery',
    answer:
      'When a person creates mental images that increase energy and/or relieve stress.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Technique imagery',
    answer: 'When individuals mentally rehearse their technique.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 4',
    topic: 'Behavioral Coaching',
    question: 'Psyching up',
    answer:
      'The process to get oneself into a state of psychological readiness for performance.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Human movement system (HMS)',
    answer:
      'The collective components and structures that work together to move the body: muscular, skeletal, and nervous systems.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Kinetic chain',
    answer:
      'A concept that describes the human body as a chain of interdependent links that work together to perform movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Nervous system',
    answer:
      'A network of specialized cells called neurons that transmit and coordinate signals, providing a communication network within the human body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Neuron',
    answer:
      'Specialized cell that is the functional unit of the nervous system.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Nucleus',
    answer:
      'Cellular structure or organelle that contains the majority of the cell’s genetic material in the form of chromosomes.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Organelles',
    answer:
      'Tiny cellular structures that perform specific functions within a cell. Examples include nuclei, mitochondria, lysosomes, ribosomes, and the endoplasmic reticulum.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Mitochondria',
    answer:
      'The parts of the cell that use nutrients to create energy for the cell; commonly known as the powerhouses of the cell.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Effector sites',
    answer:
      'A part of the body, such as a muscle or organ, that receives a signal from a neuron to produce a physiological response.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Electrolytes',
    answer:
      'Minerals that have an electrical charge to help transmit nerve impulses throughout the body, such as sodium, potassium, and magnesium.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Central nervous system (CNS)',
    answer:
      'A division of the nervous system that includes the brain and spinal cord.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Peripheral nervous system (PNS)',
    answer:
      'Nerves that connect the rest of the body to the central nervous system.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Afferent pathway',
    answer:
      'Sensory pathway that relays information to the central nervous system.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Efferent pathway',
    answer:
      'A motor pathway that relays information from the central nervous system to the rest of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Interneurons',
    answer:
      'Neurons located within the spinal cord and brain that transmit impulses between afferent and efferent neurons.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Mechanoreceptors',
    answer:
      'Specialized structures that respond to mechanical forces (touch and pressure) within tissues and then transmit signals through sensory nerves.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Somatic nervous system',
    answer:
      'Nerves that serve the outer areas of the body and skeletal muscle and are largely responsible for the voluntary control of movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Autonomic nervous system',
    answer:
      'A division of the peripheral nervous system that supplies neural input to organs that run the involuntary processes of the body (e.g., circulating blood, digesting food, producing hormones).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Sympathetic nervous system',
    answer:
      'Subdivision of the autonomic nervous system that works to increase neural activity and put the body in a heightened state.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Parasympathetic nervous system',
    answer:
      'Subdivision of the autonomic nervous system that works to decrease neural activity and put the body in a more relaxed state.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Sensory function',
    answer:
      'Ability of the nervous system to sense changes in either the internal or external environment.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Proprioception',
    answer:
      'The body’s ability to naturally sense its general orientation and relative position of its parts.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Integrative function',
    answer:
      'The ability of the nervous system to analyze and interpret the sensory information to allow for proper decision-making, which produces an appropriate response.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Motor function',
    answer:
      'The neuromuscular (or nervous and muscular systems) response to the integrated sensory information.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Muscle spindles',
    answer:
      'Sensory receptors sensitive to change in length of the muscle and the rate of that change.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Stretch reﬂex',
    answer:
      'Neurological signal from the muscle spindle that causes a muscle to contract to prevent excessive lengthening.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Golgi tendon organ (GTO)',
    answer:
      'A specialized sensory receptor located at the point where skeletal muscle fibers insert into the tendons of skeletal muscle; sensitive to changes in muscular tension and rate of tension change.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Joint receptors',
    answer:
      'Receptors located in and around the joint capsule that respond to pressure, acceleration, and deceleration of the joint.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Neuroplasticity',
    answer:
      'The concept that the brain will continually change or grow, reforming neural pathways throughout an individual’s entire life span.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Neurocircuitry',
    answer: 'The interconnection of neurons in the brain and spinal cord.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Motor skills',
    answer:
      'Specific movements through the coordinated effort of the sensory and motor subsystems.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Skeletal system',
    answer: 'A description of the bones of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Osteoporosis',
    answer:
      'A condition of reduced bone mineral density, which increases risk of bone fracture.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Joints',
    answer:
      'The sites where two bones meet and movement occurs as a result of muscle contraction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Axial skeleton',
    answer:
      'A division of the skeletal system consisting of the skull, the rib cage, and the vertebral column.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Appendicular skeleton',
    answer:
      'A division of the skeletal system consisting of the arms, legs, and pelvic girdle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Levers',
    answer: 'Rigid rods where muscles attach.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Remodeling',
    answer:
      'The process by which bone is constantly renewed by the resorption and formation of the bone structure.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Osteoclasts',
    answer: 'Special cells that break down and remove old bone tissue.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Osteoblasts',
    answer: 'Special cells that form and lay down new bone tissue.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Wolff’s law',
    answer:
      'Scientific explanation of how remodeling (new bone growth) occurs along the lines of stress placed on the bone.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Depressions',
    answer: 'Flattened or indented portions of bone.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Processes',
    answer:
      'Projections protruding from the bone where tendons and ligaments can attach.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Vertebral column',
    answer:
      'Bones that house the spinal cord; consists of the cervical, thoracic, and lumbosacral regions.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Spinal cord',
    answer: 'Bundle of nerves housed within the vertebrae.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Intervertebral discs',
    answer:
      'Fibrous cartilage structures between vertebrae that act as shock absorbers and assist with movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Neutral Spine',
    answer:
      'Represents a position in which the vertebrae and associated structures are under the least amount of load and can most optimally support functional movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Osteokinematics',
    answer: 'Movement of a limb that is visible.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Arthrokinematics',
    answer:
      'The description of joint surface movement; consists of three major types: roll, slide, and spin.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Synovial joints',
    answer: 'A joint with a fluid-filled joint capsule.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Nonaxial',
    answer:
      'A gliding joint that moves in only one plane, either back and forth or side to side.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Nonsynovial joints',
    answer:
      'Joints that have no joint capsule, fibrous connective tissue, or cartilage in the uniting structure.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Ligament',
    answer: 'A fibrous connective tissue that connects bone to bone.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Collagen',
    answer:
      'A protein found in connective tissue, muscles, and skin that provides strength and structure. It is the most abundant protein in the human body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Elastin',
    answer:
      'A protein that provides elasticity to skin, tendons, ligaments, and other structures.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Growth plate',
    answer:
      'A specialized cartilage disc located in the epiphysis that is responsible for longitudinal bone growth.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Fascia',
    answer: 'Connective tissue that surrounds muscles and bones.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Epimysium',
    answer:
      'Inner layer of fascia that directly surrounds an entire muscle, commonly referred to as the “deep fascia.”',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Fascicles',
    answer:
      'Largest bundles of fibers within a muscle. Fascicles are surrounded by perimysium.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Perimysium',
    answer: 'Connective tissue surrounding a muscle fascicle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Endomysium',
    answer:
      'Connective tissue that wraps around individual muscle fibers within a fascicle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Glycogen',
    answer:
      'Glucose that is deposited and stored in bodily tissues, such as the liver and muscle cells; the storage form of carbohydrate.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Myoglobin',
    answer:
      'Protein-based molecule that carries oxygen molecules into the muscles.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Myofibrils',
    answer:
      'The contractile components of a muscle cell; the myofilaments (actin and myosin) are contained within a myofibril.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Myofilaments',
    answer: 'The filaments of a myofibril; include actin and myosin.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Actin',
    answer:
      'The thin, stringlike, myofilament that acts along with myosin to produce muscular contraction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Myosin',
    answer:
      'The thick myofilament that acts along with actin to produce muscular contraction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Sarcomere',
    answer:
      'The structural unit of a myofibril composed of actin and myosin filaments between two Z-lines.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Z-line',
    answer: 'The meeting point of each sarcomere.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Neural activation',
    answer: 'The nervous system’s signal that tells a muscle to contract.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Neuromuscular junction',
    answer:
      'The specialized site where the nervous system communicates directly with muscle fibers.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Synapse',
    answer:
      'A junction or small gap between the motor neuron and muscle cells.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Motor unit',
    answer: 'A motor neuron and all of the muscle fibers that it innervates.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Action potential',
    answer:
      'Nerve impulse that is relayed from the central nervous system, through the peripheral nervous system, and into the muscle across the neuromuscular junction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Neurotransmitters',
    answer:
      'Chemical messengers that cross the synapse between neuron and muscle and assist with nerve transmission.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Acetylcholine (ACh)',
    answer:
      'A neurotransmitter that helps the action potential cross the synapse into the muscle, which initiates the steps in a muscle contraction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Sliding ﬁlament theory',
    answer:
      'The series of steps in muscle contraction involving how myosin (thick) and actin (thin) filaments slide past one another to produce a muscle contraction, shortening the entire length of the sarcomere.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Excitation-contraction coupling',
    answer:
      'The physiological process of converting an electrical stimulus to a muscle contraction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Power stroke',
    answer:
      'The myosin heads bind to actin and pull them toward the sarcomere center, which slides the filaments past each other, shortening the muscle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Adenosine triphosphate (ATP)',
    answer:
      'A high-energy molecule that serves as the main form of energy in the human body; known as the energy currency of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Resting length',
    answer:
      'The length of a muscle when it is not actively contracting or being stretched.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Type I muscle ﬁbers',
    answer:
      'Muscle fibers that are small in size, generate lower amounts of force, and are more resistant to fatigue.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Type II muscle ﬁbers',
    answer:
      'Muscle fibers that are larger in size, generate higher amounts of force, and are faster to fatigue.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'All-or-nothing principle',
    answer:
      'Motor units cannot vary the amount of force they generate; they either contract maximally or not at all.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 5',
    topic: 'The Nervous, Skeletal, and Muscular Systems',
    question: 'Capillaries',
    answer:
      'The smallest blood vessels and the site of exchange of elements between the blood and the tissues.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Cardiorespiratory system',
    answer:
      'A system of the body composed of the heart, blood, blood vessels, lungs, and airways.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Cardiovascular system',
    answer:
      'A system of the body, also known as the circulatory system, that transports blood to tissues of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Thoracic cavity',
    answer: 'Chamber within the chest that contains the heart and lungs.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Mediastinum',
    answer:
      'The space in the chest between the lungs that contains all the internal organs of the chest (e.g., heart, esophagus) except the lungs.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Cardiac muscle',
    answer: 'Muscle of the heart.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Smooth muscle',
    answer: 'An involuntary nonstriated muscle type that is found in organs.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Atrium (atria)',
    answer:
      'Superior chamber(s) of the heart that gathers blood returning to the heart.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Ventricle',
    answer:
      'Inferior chamber of the heart that pumps blood to the lungs and body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Intercalated discs',
    answer:
      'Found in the heart, these formations help hold together muscle cells.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Resting heart rate (RHR)',
    answer: 'The number of heart beats per minute while at complete rest.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Sinoatrial (SA) node',
    answer:
      'Located in the right atrium, this node initiates an electrical signal that causes the heart to beat.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Atrioventricular (AV) node',
    answer:
      'Located between the atria and ventricles, this node delays the impulse from the sinoatrial node before allowing it to pass to the ventricles.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Stroke volume',
    answer:
      'The amount of blood pumped out of the heart with each contraction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'End-diastolic volume',
    answer: 'The filled volume of the ventricle before contraction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'End-systolic volume',
    answer: 'The volume of blood remaining in the ventricle after ejection.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Heart rate (HR)',
    answer:
      'The measurement of the number of times a heart beats within a specified time period (usually 1 minute).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Bradycardia',
    answer: 'When the heart rate is less than 60 beats per minute.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Tachycardia',
    answer: 'When the heart rate is greater than 100 beats per minute.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Cardiac output (Q)',
    answer:
      'The overall performance of the heart (heart rate × stroke volume).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Blood',
    answer:
      'Fluid that circulates in the heart, arteries, capillaries, and veins; it carries nutrients and oxygen to all parts of the body and also transports waste products from the body to other compartments or organs for either processing (e.g., liver) or excretion (e.g., kidney).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Growth factors',
    answer:
      'Substances within the blood that attach to cells, aid in growth and development, and help with healing after injury',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Stem cells',
    answer:
      'Cells within the body that divide and develop into specialized cells, such as brain cells, blood cells, heart cells, and bone cells.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Blood vessels',
    answer:
      'Network of hollow tubes that circulates blood throughout the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Arteries',
    answer: 'Vessels that transport blood away from the heart.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Veins',
    answer: 'Vessels that transport blood back to the heart.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Arterioles',
    answer: 'Small arteries that eventually divide into capillaries.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Venules',
    answer:
      'Small veins that allows blood to drain from capillaries into the larger veins.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Vasculogenesis',
    answer: 'The formation of new capillaries.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Angiogenesis',
    answer: 'The formation of new capillaries from existing blood vessels.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Venous pooling',
    answer:
      'The accumulation of blood into the extremities due to slow blood flow though the veins (venous return) or backflow.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Blood pressure (BP)',
    answer:
      'The outward pressure exerted by the blood on the vessel walls; reported as systolic/ diastolic.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Peripheral resistance',
    answer:
      'The amount of resistance in the arteries that must be overcome for blood to flow.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Respiratory system',
    answer:
      'A bodily system, also known as the pulmonary system, that brings oxygen into the lungs from breathed air while removing carbon dioxide from the lungs into the outside air; includes airways, lungs, and the respiratory muscles.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Respiratory pump',
    answer:
      'Composed of skeletal structures (bones) and soft tissues (muscles) that work together to allow for proper respiratory mechanics as well as pumping blood back to the heart during inspiration.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Inspiration',
    answer:
      'The process of contracting the inspiratory muscles to move air into the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Expiration',
    answer:
      'The process of actively or passively relaxing the inspiratory muscles to move air out of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Valsalva maneuver',
    answer:
      'A process that involves expiring against a closed windpipe, creating additional intra-abdominal pressure and spinal stability.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Diffusion',
    answer:
      'The process of getting oxygen from the environment to the tissues of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Tachypnea',
    answer:
      'Respiratory rate that is too fast; greater than 24 breaths per minute.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Bradypnea',
    answer:
      'Respiratory rate that is too slow; fewer than 8 breaths per minute.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Dyspnea',
    answer: 'Shortness of breath or labored breathing.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Diaphragmatic breathing',
    answer: 'Breathing deeply by allowing the expansion of the abdominal area.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Lipolysis',
    answer: 'The breakdown and utilization of fat for energy.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Enzyme',
    answer:
      'A substance in the body that causes a specific reaction or change.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Glands',
    answer:
      'Cells that release substances into the bloodstream (such as hormones) or other surface of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Hormone',
    answer:
      'Chemical messenger released from a gland that travels to cells to activate a specific function.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Target (receptor) cell',
    answer:
      'Cell that receives a message from a hormone or enzyme. Target cells exert an action after being stimulated or activated.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Hypothalamus',
    answer:
      'A gland located in the brain that communicates with the pituitary gland.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Pineal gland',
    answer:
      'A small gland in the brain that secretes the hormone melatonin, which helps regulate sleep cycles.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Pancreas',
    answer:
      'An organ with numerous functions, including the production of insulin, glucagon, and digestive juices.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Thyroid gland',
    answer:
      'An endocrine gland, located in the anterior neck, responsible for the secretion of many hormones, including thyroxin and calcitonin.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Pituitary gland',
    answer:
      'An endocrine gland that controls the secretion of many hormones, including growth hormone.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Adrenal gland',
    answer:
      'A gland, located just above the kidneys, responsible for the secretion of catecholamines and cortisol.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Reproductive glands',
    answer:
      'Glands, such as the ovaries or testes, that serve sex-specific functions.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Insulin',
    answer:
      'A hormone secreted by the pancreas that is responsible for glucose metabolism.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Glucagon',
    answer:
      'A hormone secreted by the pancreas that regulates blood glucose and functions opposite to insulin.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Substrates',
    answer:
      'Intermediate forms of nutrients used in metabolic reactions to create adenosine triphosphate.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Growth hormone',
    answer:
      'An anabolic hormone produced by the pituitary gland that is responsible for growth and development.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Catecholamines',
    answer:
      'Hormones produced by the adrenal glands that are part of the stress response known as the fight-or-flight response.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Catabolic',
    answer:
      'Metabolic process that breaks down molecules into smaller units used for energy.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Gluconeogenesis',
    answer:
      'The formation of glucose from noncarbohydrate sources (proteins and fats).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Overtraining',
    answer:
      'Excessive frequency, volume, or intensity of training, resulting in reduction of performance, which is also caused by a lack of proper rest and recovery.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Testosterone',
    answer: 'A hormone producing secondary male sex characteristics.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Anabolic',
    answer:
      'Metabolic process that synthesizes smaller molecules into larger units used for building and repairing tissues.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Insulin-like growth factors (IGF)',
    answer:
      'Anabolic hormone produced by the liver, which is responsible for growth and development.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Basal metabolic rate (BMR)',
    answer: 'The amount of energy required to maintain the body at rest.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Calcitonin',
    answer:
      'Thyroid hormone that helps the body use calcium properly to aid with maintaining bone mineral density.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Glucose intolerance',
    answer: 'A condition that results in elevated blood glucose levels.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Gall bladder',
    answer:
      'An organ found below the liver, on the right side of the body, that receives bile from the liver and secretes it into the duodenum.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Liver',
    answer:
      'An organ in the upper-right abdominal cavity with numerous functions, including the production and secretion of bile, which is stored and concentrated in the gall bladder prior to release into the duodenum.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Motility',
    answer:
      'In the digestive system, refers to movements of the anatomical structures that allow contents to pass through.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Mastication',
    answer: 'The mechanical process whereby the oral muscles break down food.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Peristalsis',
    answer:
      'The muscle action of the gastrointestinal system that pushes food through the body during digestion.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Digestion',
    answer:
      'Multistep process that describes the passage of food through the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Absorption',
    answer:
      'The process of nutrients being absorbed into the body during the digestive process.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Esophagus',
    answer:
      'The anatomical part of the digestive tract that allows food to pass from oral cavity to stomach.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Ingestion',
    answer:
      'The act of taking food, liquid, or other substances into the body in preparation for digestion.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Chyme',
    answer:
      'A semifluid mass of digested food that is passed from the stomach to the small intestine.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Duodenum',
    answer:
      'Part of the small intestine that resides between the stomach and the jejunum.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Jejunum',
    answer:
      'Part of the small intestine that resides between the duodenum and the ileum.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 6',
    topic: 'The Cardiorespiratory, Endocrine, and Digestive Systems',
    question: 'Ileum',
    answer:
      'The final section of the small intestine, located between the jejunum and the cecum and leads to the large intestine.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Human movement system (HMS)',
    answer:
      'The collective components and structures that work together to move the body: muscular, skeletal, and nervous systems.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Regional interdependence model',
    answer:
      'The concept describing the integrated functioning of multiple body systems or regions of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Biomechanics',
    answer:
      'The science concerned with the internal and external forces acting on the human body and the effects produced by these forces.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Anatomic position',
    answer:
      'The position with the body erect, the arms at the sides, and the palms forward. It is the position of reference for anatomic nomenclature.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Sagittal plane',
    answer:
      'An imaginary bisector that divides the body into left and right halves.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Flexion',
    answer:
      'A bending movement in which the relative angle between two adjacent segments decreases.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Extension',
    answer:
      'A straightening movement in which the relative angle between two adjacent segments increases.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Hyperextension',
    answer: 'Extension of a joint beyond the normal limit or range of motion.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Dorsiflexion',
    answer: 'Flexion occurring at the ankle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Plantar flexion',
    answer: 'Extension occurring at the ankle. Pointing the foot downwards.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Frontal plane',
    answer:
      'An imaginary bisector that divides the body into front and back halves. Movement in the frontal plane includes abduction, adduction, and side-to-side motions.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Abduction',
    answer:
      'A movement in the frontal plane away from the midline of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Adduction',
    answer:
      'Movement in the frontal plane back toward the midline of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Lateral flexion',
    answer: 'Bending of the spine from side to side.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Eversion',
    answer:
      'A movement in which the inferior calcaneus (heel bone) moves laterally. The bottom of foot faces outward.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Inversion',
    answer:
      'A movement in which the inferior calcaneus (heel bone) moves medially. Bottom of foot faces inward.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Transverse plane',
    answer:
      'An imaginary bisector that divides the body into top and bottom halves.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Internal rotation',
    answer: 'Rotation of a body segment toward the middle of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'External rotation',
    answer: 'Rotation of a body segment away from the middle of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Horizontal abduction',
    answer:
      'Movement of the arm or thigh in the transverse plane from an anterior position to a lateral position.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Horizontal adduction',
    answer:
      'Movement of the arm or thigh in the transverse plane from a lateral position to an anterior position.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Radioulnar pronation',
    answer:
      'Inward rotation of the forearm from a palm-up position to a palm-down position.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Radioulnar supination',
    answer:
      'Outward rotation of the forearm from a palm-down position to a palm-up position.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Pronation of the foot',
    answer:
      'Multiplanar movement of the foot and ankle complex consisting of eversion, dorsiflexion, and ankle abduction; associated with force reduction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Supination of the foot',
    answer:
      'Multiplanar movement of the foot and ankle complex consisting of inversion, plantar flexion, and ankle adduction; associated with force production.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Gait',
    answer:
      'Biomechanical motion of the lower extremities during walking, running, and sprinting.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Scapular retraction',
    answer: 'Adduction of scapulae; shoulder blades move toward the midline.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Scapular protraction',
    answer:
      'Abduction of scapulae; shoulder blades move away from the midline.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Scapular depression',
    answer: 'Downward (inferior) motion of the scapulae.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Scapular elevation',
    answer: 'Upward (superior) motion of the scapulae.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Elasticity',
    answer:
      'The ability of soft tissues to return to resting length after being stretched.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Flexibility',
    answer:
      'The normal extensibility of soft tissues that allows for full range of motion of a joint.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Hypermobility',
    answer:
      'A state where a lack of neuromuscular support leads to a joint having more range of motion than it should, greatly increasing the risk of injury at that joint.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Hypomobility',
    answer: 'When range of motion at a joint is limited.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Eccentric muscle action',
    answer:
      'A muscle action that occurs when a muscle develops tension while lengthening.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Concentric muscle action',
    answer:
      'A muscle action that occurs when a muscle is exerting force greater than the resistive force, resulting in a shortening of the muscle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Isometric muscle action',
    answer:
      'When a muscle is exerting force equal to the force being placed on it leading to no visible change in the muscle length.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Core',
    answer:
      'The structures that make up the lumbo-pelvic-hip complex (LPHC), including the lumbar spine, pelvic girdle, abdomen, and hip joint.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Muscle action spectrum',
    answer:
      'The full range of eccentric, isometric, and concentric muscle contractions required to perform a movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Agonists',
    answer: 'The primary muscles providing force for a movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Synergists',
    answer: 'Muscles that assist agonists to produce a movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Stabilizers',
    answer:
      'Muscles that contract isometrically to stabilize the trunk and joints as the body moves.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Feed-forward activation',
    answer:
      'When a muscle is automatically activated in anticipation of a movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Antagonists',
    answer:
      'Muscles on the opposite side of a joint that are in direct opposition of agonist muscles.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Force',
    answer:
      'An influence applied by one object to another, which results in an acceleration or deceleration of the second object.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Length-tension relationship',
    answer:
      'The resting length of a muscle and the tension the muscle can produce at this resting length.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Muscle balance',
    answer:
      'When all muscles surrounding a joint have optimal length-tension relationships, allowing the joint to rest in a neutral position.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Altered length-tension relationship',
    answer:
      'When a muscle’s resting length is too short or too long, reducing the amount of force it can produce.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Reciprocal inhibition',
    answer:
      'When an agonist receives a signal to contract, its functional antagonist also receives an inhibitory signal allowing it to lengthen.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Altered reciprocal inhibition',
    answer:
      'Occurs when an overactive agonist muscle decreases the neural drive to its functional antagonist.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Neutral position',
    answer:
      'The optimal resting position of a joint that allows it to function efficiently through its entire normal range of motion.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Stretch-shortening cycle',
    answer:
      'Loading of a muscle eccentrically to prepare it for a rapid concentric contraction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Series elastic component',
    answer:
      'Springlike noncontractile component of muscle and tendon that stores elastic energy.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Amortization phase',
    answer:
      'The transition from eccentric loading to concentric unloading during the stretch-shortening cycle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Stretch reflex',
    answer:
      'Neurological signal from the muscle spindle that causes a muscle to contract to prevent excessive lengthening.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Integrated performance paradigm',
    answer:
      'To move with efficiency, forces must be dampened (eccentrically), stabilized (isometrically), and then accelerated (concentrically).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Tendon',
    answer: 'A fibrous connective tissue that connects muscle to bone.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Force-couple relationship',
    answer:
      'The synergistic action of multiple muscles working together to produce movement around a joint.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Joint support systems',
    answer:
      'Muscular stabilization systems located in joints distal of the spine.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Rotary motion',
    answer: 'Movement of the bones around the joints.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Torque',
    answer:
      'A force that produces rotation; common unit of measurement is the Newton meter (Nm).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Motor behavior',
    answer: 'Motor response to internal and external environmental stimuli.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Motor control',
    answer:
      'How the central nervous system integrates internal and external sensory information with previous experiences to produce a motor response.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Motor learning',
    answer:
      'Integration of motor control processes through practice and experience, leading to a relatively permanent change in the capacity to produce skilled motor behavior.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Motor development',
    answer:
      'Change in skilled motor behavior over time throughout the life span.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Muscle synergies',
    answer:
      'Groups of muscles that are recruited simultaneously by the central nervous system to provide movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Sensorimotor integration',
    answer:
      'Cooperation of the nervous and muscular system in gathering and interpreting information and executing movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Feedback',
    answer:
      'Use of sensory information and sensorimotor integration to help the human movement system in motor learning.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Internal feedback',
    answer:
      'Process whereby sensory information is used by the body to reactively monitor movement and the environment.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'External feedback',
    answer:
      'Information provided by some external source, such as a fitness professional, video, mirror, or heart rate monitor, to supplement the internal environment.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 7',
    topic: 'Human Movement Science',
    question: 'Neuromuscular efficiency',
    answer:
      'The ability of the nervous system to recruit the correct muscles to produce force, reduce force, and dynamically stabilize the body’s structure in all three planes of motion.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Bioenergetics',
    answer: 'The study of energy in the human body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Metabolism',
    answer:
      'All of the chemical reactions that occur in the body to maintain itself.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Exercise metabolism',
    answer:
      'The examination of bioenergetics as it relates to the unique physiologic changes and demands placed on the body during exercise.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'First law of thermodynamics',
    answer:
      'Energy cannot be created or destroyed but merely converted from one form to another.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Macronutrients',
    answer:
      'Food substances required in large amounts to supply energy and include protein, carbohydrate, and fat.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Ventilatory threshold 1 (VT1)',
    answer:
      'The point at which the body uses an equal mix of carbohydrate and fat as fuel sources.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Ventilatory threshold 2 (VT2)',
    answer:
      'The point where glucose provides nearly all of the energy for the activity.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Fats',
    answer:
      'One of the three main classes of foods and a source of energy in the body. Fats help the body use some vitamins and keep the skin healthy. They also serve as energy stores for the body. In food, there are two types of fats: saturated and unsaturated.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Triglyceride',
    answer:
      'The chemical or substrate form in which most fat exists in food as well as in the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Free fatty acids',
    answer:
      'The by-products of the breakdown of stored or consumed fats, metabolized exclusively via the aerobic pathway, which uses oxygen to create adenosine triphosphate.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Protein',
    answer:
      'Amino acids linked by peptide bonds; the building blocks of body tissues.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Essential amino acid (EAA)',
    answer:
      'Amino acid that must be obtained through the diet as the body does not make it; there are nine essential amino acids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Nonessential amino acids',
    answer:
      'Amino acids that can be synthesized by the body and do not, under normal circumstances, need to be obtained in the diet.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Negative energy balance',
    answer:
      'When calorie intake is lower than the number of calories expended.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Ketogenesis',
    answer:
      'The formation of ketone bodies from nonfat sources, such as certain amino acids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Ketone bodies',
    answer:
      'Water-soluble molecules produced in the liver as a result of fatty acid oxidation. They can then be oxidized in the mitochondria to produce adenosine triphosphate.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Ketosis',
    answer:
      'A state of carbohydrate depletion where the liver manufactures ketone bodies to meet energy demands that free fatty acid oxidation cannot support.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Exogenous ketones',
    answer: 'Isolated ketone bodies usually consumed in supplement form.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Ketoacidosis',
    answer:
      'Metabolic acidosis induced by very high levels of ketone bodies such as seen in type 1 diabetes or severe insulin resistance.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Mechanical work',
    answer:
      'The physical processes that move the body and keep it alive, such as muscle contraction.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Adenosine diphosphate (ADP)',
    answer:
      'A high-energy compound occurring in all cells from which adenosine triphosphate is formed.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Phosphorylation',
    answer:
      'The addition of a phosphate group to a molecule, such as in the transfer of a phosphate group to adenosine diphosphate to create adenosine triphosphate.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'ATP-PC System',
    answer:
      'An energy system that provides energy very rapidly, for approximately 10–15 seconds, via anaerobic metabolism.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Anaerobic',
    answer: 'Processes relating to the absence of oxygen.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Glycolysis',
    answer:
      'A metabolic process that occurs in the cytosol of a cell that converts glucose into pyruvate and adenosine triphosphate. Anaerobic glycolysis refers to when this process occurs in the absence of oxygen.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Oxidative phosphorylation',
    answer:
      'A series of reactions inside the mitochondria that uses oxygen to produce adenosine triphosphate.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Aerobic',
    answer: 'Processes relating to, involving, or requiring oxygen.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Deamination',
    answer:
      'The breakdown of amino acids into substrates that can be used for energy metabolism.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Electron transport chain (ETC)',
    answer:
      'A series of protein complexes that transfer protons and electrons received from the citric acid cycle through a series of reactions to create adenosine triphosphate.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Acetyl coenzyme A',
    answer:
      'Produced by the breakdown of carbohydrates through glycolysis and by the fatty acids through beta-oxidation and is the precursor for these substrates to the citric acid cycle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Beta-oxidation',
    answer:
      'The first step in the process to break down fats via oxidative phosphorylation.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Steady-state aerobic exercise',
    answer:
      'Aerobic exercise that remains at a relatively constant intensity, including a stable heart rate and oxygen consumption.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Excess postexercise oxygen consumption (EPOC)',
    answer:
      'The state in which the body’s metabolism is elevated after exercise.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Total daily energy expenditure (TDEE)',
    answer: 'The total amount of energy expended in one day.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Kilocalorie (kcal)',
    answer:
      'One food calorie. Also, the amount of energy needed to raise one kilogram of water by one degree Celsius.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Resting metabolic rate (RMR)',
    answer:
      'The rate at which the body expends energy (calories) when fasted and at complete rest, such as asleep or lying quietly.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Exercise activity thermogenesis (EAT)',
    answer: 'The calories expended through structured exercise or training.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Thermic effect of food (TEF)',
    answer:
      'The energy required to digest, absorb, and process nutrients that are consumed.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Nonexercise activity thermogenesis (NEAT)',
    answer:
      'Energy expenditure through daily activities outside of structured exercise, such as walking, completing household chores, and taking the stairs.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Physical activity level (PAL)',
    answer:
      'The number of calories a person expends through physical activity and structured exercise.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 8',
    topic: 'Exercise Metabolism and Bioenergetics',
    question: 'Metabolic equivalent (MET)',
    answer:
      'A measurement used to describe the energy cost of physical activity as multiples of resting metabolic rate. One MET is 3.5 mL of oxygen consumption per kilogram per minute.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Nutrition',
    answer:
      'A process of obtaining nutrients through food and/or food products to support energy requirements and cellular processes, including growth, repair and maintenance of tissues, reproduction, digestive processes, and respiration.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'CDN',
    answer:
      'Certified Dietitian Nutritionist: state certified dietitian/nutritionist.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Scope of practice',
    answer:
      'The actions that a professional is permitted to undertake in keeping with the terms of their license or certification.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Nutrition claim',
    answer:
      'Claim that a food has a specific nutritional property or provides a specific benefit.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Micronutrients',
    answer:
      'Vitamins, minerals, and phytonutrients. These are nonenergy yielding nutrients that have important regulatory functions in metabolic pathways.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Vitamins',
    answer:
      'Group of organic compounds required in small quantities in the diet to support growth and metabolic processes.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Minerals',
    answer:
      'Inorganic, natural substances, some of which are essential in human nutrition. There are two kinds of minerals: major minerals (aka, macrominerals) and trace minerals.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Amino acids',
    answer:
      'Organic building blocks of proteins containing both a carboxyl and an amino group.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Peptide bond',
    answer: 'A chemical bond that connects two amino acids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Protein turnover',
    answer:
      'A process in which the body breaks down existing proteins and recycles the component amino acids for incorporation into new proteins or other nitrogen-containing compounds.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Complete protein',
    answer: 'A protein source that provides all essential amino acids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Incomplete protein',
    answer:
      'A protein that lacks one or more of the amino acids required to build cells.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Omnivorous diet',
    answer: 'A diet that consists of both animals and plants.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Mutual supplementation',
    answer:
      'Combination of two incomplete protein sources that together provide all of the essential amino acids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Protein quality',
    answer:
      'Refers to the amino acid profile and the digestibility of a protein source.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Low biological value (LBV) proteins',
    answer: 'Foods missing one or more of the essential amino acids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'High biological value (HBV) proteins',
    answer: 'Foods containing all the essential amino acids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Protein efficiency ratio (PER)',
    answer:
      'A measure of assessing proteins, based on the amount of weight gained by a test subject divided by the amount of intake of a protein food.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Biological value (BV)',
    answer:
      'A reference amount used to describe the extent to which the amino acids in a protein source are absorbed.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Protein digestibility– corrected amino acid score (PDCAAS)',
    answer:
      'A measure for evaluating a protein source based on the composition of amino acids and its digestibility.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Net protein utilization (NPU)',
    answer:
      'The ratio of amino acid mass turned into proteins compared to the total amino acid mass consumed in the diet.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Enterocyte',
    answer: 'Intestinal cells that absorb nutrients.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Recommended dietary allowance (RDA)',
    answer:
      'The recommended amount of a nutrient that meets the needs of most healthy individuals within specific age and gender groups.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Acceptable macronutrient distribution range (AMDR)',
    answer:
      'Ranges of intake for nutrients that are estimated to meet the needs of 97–98% of the population and that are associated with a reduced risk of chronic disease. AMDRs are established by the National Academy of Medicine.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Carbohydrates',
    answer:
      'Compounds composed of carbon, hydrogen, and oxygen molecules that include simple sugars, complex carbohydrates, glycogen, and fiber.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Simple sugars',
    answer:
      'Include the monosaccharides and disaccharides; easily absorbed into the bloodstream.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Monosaccharides',
    answer:
      'Simplest form of carbohydrate; single sugar molecules (e.g., glucose).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Disaccharides',
    answer:
      'Two monosaccharides joined together to form a simple sugar. The three disaccharides of nutritional importance include lactose, sucrose, and maltose.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Polysaccharides',
    answer:
      'A type of carbohydrate composed of long chains of glucose units; starch and glycogen are examples of polysaccharides.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Starch',
    answer: 'Storage form of carbohydrate in plants.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Fiber',
    answer:
      'An indigestible carbohydrate present in plant foods, such as fruit, vegetables, and legumes.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Adipose tissue',
    answer: 'An alternative term for fat, used primarily to store energy.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Complex carbohydrates',
    answer:
      'Polysaccharides; long chains of simple sugars. Examples include whole grains, legumes, and vegetables.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Glycemic index (GI)',
    answer:
      'Number (0–100) assigned to a food source that represents the rise in blood sugar after consuming the food.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Glycemic load (GL)',
    answer:
      'Similar to glycemic index but takes into account the amount of food (carbohydrate) eaten.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Muscle protein synthesis',
    answer:
      'Process by which new muscle proteins are formed and a muscle grows or repairs at the molecular level.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Lipids',
    answer:
      'Group of fats/fatty acids and their derivatives, including triglycerides, phospholipids, and sterols.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Triglycerides',
    answer:
      'The chemical or substrate form in which most fat exists in food as well as in the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Phospholipids',
    answer:
      'Type of lipid (fat) comprised of glycerol, two fatty acid chains, and a phosphate group.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Sterols',
    answer:
      'A group of lipids with a ringlike structure. Cholesterol is a type of sterol.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Unsaturated fats',
    answer:
      'Fatty acids with one or more points of unsaturation (double bond) in their chemical structure.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Saturated fat',
    answer:
      'A type of triglyceride; chemical structure has no double bonds (points of unsaturation); usually solid at room temperature. Examples: butter, lard, whole milk, beef, processed meats, and tropical oils.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Pancreatic enzymes',
    answer:
      'Digestive enzymes produced by the body to help digest fats, starches, and proteins.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Lingual lipase',
    answer:
      'An enzyme in saliva that begins the process of lipid digestion in the mouth.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Lipase',
    answer: 'Enzyme that digests lipids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Chylomicrons',
    answer:
      'Molecules of fat that contain triglycerides, phospholipids, cholesterol, fat-soluble vitamins, and protein. They are formed by intestinal cells after the digestion of lipid-containing foods.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Lipoprotein',
    answer:
      'A group of soluble proteins that combine with and transport fat or other lipids in the blood plasma.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Lipoprotein lipase (LPL)',
    answer: 'An enzyme that breaks down triglycerides into fatty acids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Metabolites',
    answer: 'The formation of a substance required for metabolism.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Major minerals',
    answer: 'Minerals present in the body in larger amounts.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Trace minerals',
    answer:
      'Minerals present in small amounts in the body. They include iron, zinc, copper, selenium, iodine, manganese, chromium, fluoride, and molybdenum.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Heat exhaustion',
    answer:
      'A condition that occurs when the body becomes overheated. It can occur from dehydration in a hot climate, and symptoms include heavy sweating, rapid pulse, low blood pressure, nausea, dizziness, and muscle cramps.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Heatstroke',
    answer:
      'A condition that can develop if heat exhaustion is not treated quickly. Heatstroke symptoms include headache, fever, confusion and disorientation, and flushed skin. Heatstroke is a medical emergency and can be fatal if not quickly treated.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Sports drink',
    answer:
      'Drink with a combination of carbohydrate and/or electrolytes used for rehydration and carbohydrate replenishment during physical activity; may be isotonic, hypotonic, or hypertonic.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Hypotonic',
    answer:
      'A solution with a lower solute load/concentration than body fluids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Isotonic',
    answer:
      'A solution with a similar solute load/concentration as body fluids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Hypertonic',
    answer:
      'A solution with a higher solute load/concentration than body fluids.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Endocrine (hormonal) disorders',
    answer:
      'When the body produces too little or too much of an endocrine hormone.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Added sugars',
    answer:
      'Sugars that are not naturally found in food but have been added to a food product.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Satiating',
    answer: 'Satisfying; feeling of fullness.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Peptide YY',
    answer:
      'Called peptide tyrosine and is a peptide that is released in the colon during feeding.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Ghrelin',
    answer: 'The hunger hormone that stimulates appetite.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Hypothyroidism',
    answer:
      'Low activity of the thyroid gland that can disrupt heart rate, body temperature, and metabolism.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: "Cushing's syndrome",
    answer:
      'A hormone disorder that causes abnormally high levels of cortisol in the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Polycystic ovarian syndrome (PCOS)',
    answer:
      'A hormone disorder that occurs in women of childbearing age that causes irregular periods, excess levels of the male hormone androgen, small cysts on the outer edges of the ovaries, and obesity.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Adaptive thermogenesis',
    answer:
      'Metabolic adaptations and changes in energy expenditure as a result of changes in energy intake.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Ingredients list',
    answer:
      'A list of all included ingredients in a food product, in descending order of amount by weight, on a food label.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Nutrition facts panel',
    answer:
      'Label on food products that provides information on the nutrient content of the food. Lists servings per container, serving size, and the amount of specific nutrients.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Serving size',
    answer:
      'A reference amount based on the quantity of the product consumers are thought to typically consume at one sitting.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Percent daily value (%DV)',
    answer:
      'A reference value on the nutrition label that indicates what percentage of the recommended daily value for a nutrient is met by the specified serving size of a food product, based on a 2,000-calorie diet.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Percent reference intake (% RI)',
    answer:
      'Used on food labels in the United Kingdom and the European Union. It is a reference value that indicates what percentage of the recommend amount of a nutrient is met by the specified amount (100 g or 100 mL) of the food product.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 9',
    topic: 'Nutrition',
    question: 'Hypertrophy',
    answer:
      'Enlargement of an organ or tissue; in the context of fitness, it is often used to describe the enlargement of skeletal muscle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Dietary supplement',
    answer:
      'A product (other than tobacco) intended to supplement the diet that bears or contains one or more of the following dietary ingredients: vitamin; mineral; herb or other botanical; amino acid; substance used by man to supplement the diet by increasing the total dietary intake; or concentrate, metabolite, constituent, extract, or combination of any previously described ingredient.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Essential nutrient',
    answer:
      'Must be obtained in the diet, as the body is incapable of producing the nutrient on its own.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Toxicity',
    answer:
      'When too much of a vitamin or mineral accumulates within the body, resulting in illness or other symptoms.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Dietary Supplement Health and Education Act of 1994',
    answer:
      'The primary legislation of the U.S. government regulating dietary supplements.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Code of Federal Regulations',
    answer:
      'Describes the laws and regulations for dietary supplements, including how supplements are labeled, manufactured, and brought to or removed from market.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Tolerable upper limit',
    answer:
      'The greatest quantity of a vitamin or mineral that may be consumed in a day without risk of an adverse health effect.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Adverse effect',
    answer:
      'Any unfavorable medical occurrence associated with the use of a medication, medical intervention, or dietary supplement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Stimulant',
    answer:
      'An agent that increases physiologic or metabolic activity. Common stimulants include caffeine and nicotine.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Creatine',
    answer:
      'Molecule made from amino acids and used as a dietary supplement to facilitate adenosine triphosphate regeneration for improved training capacity, strength, power, and muscle mass.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Banned',
    answer:
      'A dietary supplement that may be prohibited from use in a specific sport or sport league. These supplements may not be illegal or prohibited at all times during the year.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Anabolic steroid',
    answer:
      'Compound made from testosterone or another hormone that acts on hormone receptors to produce increases in muscle size or strength.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Active ingredient',
    answer:
      'Any component of a dietary supplement included for the purpose of causing a physiologic effect; displayed on the main body of the supplement facts panel.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Other ingredient',
    answer:
      'Any component of a dietary supplement included for taste, bulk, or as a preservative; displayed beneath the main body of the supplement facts panel.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Supplement facts panel',
    answer:
      'Portion of a dietary supplement’s label that displays the active ingredients, other ingredients, serving size, number of servings, quantity of ingredients, and the percent daily value.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Daily value (DV)',
    answer:
      'Amount of a nutrient recommended to be consumed each day to maintain good health. Based on a 2,000-calorie diet for those ages 4 years and older.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Health supplement',
    answer: 'A dietary supplement used to improve a component of well-being.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Performance supplement',
    answer:
      'A dietary supplement that may enhance performance or body composition; may also be referred to as an ergogenic aid.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Biologically active',
    answer:
      'The form in which a vitamin must be to exert an effect within the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Biologically inactive',
    answer: 'Any form of vitamin that cannot exert its effect within the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Beta-carotene',
    answer:
      'The red-orange pigment found in vegetables and fruits that is converted to vitamin A in the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Lactose intolerance',
    answer:
      'A sensitivity to lactose (milk sugar) typically resulting in gastrointestinal distress.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Irritable bowel syndrome',
    answer:
      'Gastrointestinal discomfort, sometimes severe, triggered by certain foods but is not a food allergy.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Rickets',
    answer: 'A bone weakness disease caused by vitamin D deficiency.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Heart arrhythmias',
    answer: 'Irregular heartbeat.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Platelet aggregation',
    answer: 'An accumulation of blood cells prior to a clot.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Immunodeﬁciency',
    answer: 'A weakened immune system.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Peripheral neuropathy',
    answer: 'Nerve damage not occurring in the brain or spinal cord.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Skeletal myopathy',
    answer: 'Muscle degeneration.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Scurvy',
    answer:
      'A disease resulting from insufficient vitamin C and characterized by spontaneous bleeding (usually of the gums), anemia, swelling, weakened joints, and loss of teeth.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Beriberi',
    answer:
      'A thiamine deficiency that can result in inflammation or degeneration of the heart and nerves, peripheral neuropathy, and impaired motor function.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Pellagra',
    answer:
      'A niacin or tryptophan deficiency that leads to a skin rash (dermatitis), digestive disorders (diarrhea), and mood or cognitive decline (dementia).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Anorexia',
    answer:
      'A loss of appetite or the conscious decision to avoid eating, often leading to dangerously low body weight and/or malnourishment.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Anemia',
    answer: 'A condition of poor iron status.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Dermatitis',
    answer:
      'Inflammation of the skin, rashes, excessive dryness, and/or blistering.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Spina biﬁda',
    answer:
      'A birth defect, and type of neural tube defect, when the spine and spinal cord do not form properly.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Amenorrheic',
    answer: 'Absence of menstruation.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Osteopenia',
    answer: 'Lower than normal bone density and a precursor to osteoporosis.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Lacto-ovo vegetarian',
    answer: 'A vegetarian diet that also includes dairy and eggs.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Ovo-vegetarian',
    answer: 'A vegetarian diet that also includes eggs.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Hypercalcemia',
    answer: 'Excess blood calcium levels.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Heme',
    answer: 'A type of iron found in animal foods.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Nonheme',
    answer: 'A type of iron found in plant foods.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Hemochromatosis',
    answer:
      'A disease in which the body absorbs too much iron from consumed foods.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Omega-3',
    answer:
      'The polyunsaturated fats, eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA), docosahexaenoic acid (DHA), and alpha-linolenic acid (ALA).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA)',
    answer:
      'A type of omega-3 fatty acid found in the flesh of cold-water fish, such as tuna, mackerel, salmon, and herring.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Docosahexaenoic acid (DHA)',
    answer:
      'A type of omega-3 fatty acid that is found in seafood, such as fish and fish oils.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Alpha-linolenic acid (ALA)',
    answer:
      'One type of omega-3 fatty acid found in seeds and oils, such as walnuts and flaxseed, and many common vegetable oils.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Ergogenic aid',
    answer:
      'A dietary supplement that may enhance performance or body composition; it may also be referred to as a performance supplement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Branched chain amino acids  (BCAAs)',
    answer:
      'The three essential amino acids (leucine, isoleucine, and valine) that are abundant in skeletal muscle tissue and named for their branchlike structures.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Muscle protein synthesis (MPS)',
    answer:
      'Process by which new muscle proteins are formed and a muscle grows or repairs at the molecular level.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Phosphagen',
    answer:
      'High-energy molecule that releases energy when its bonds are broken.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Creatine monohydrate',
    answer:
      'The most common, and likely most effective, form of creatine available as a dietary supplement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Loading',
    answer:
      'Practice of using large doses of a supplement to saturate muscle tissues or other body stores prior to resorting to a lesser, maintenance dose.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Endogenous',
    answer: 'Produced or synthesized within an organism.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Adrenaline',
    answer:
      'Hormone, also known as epinephrine, that excites bodily processes, increasing alertness and cell metabolism.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Caffeine anhydrous',
    answer:
      'A highly concentrated caffeine powder made from the seeds and leaves of coffee plants.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'DMAA',
    answer:
      'Dimethylamylamine; a stimulant and amphetamine once legal for use as a dietary supplement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Ephedra',
    answer:
      'A plant-sourced alkaloid with metabolism-enhancing effects. It is an illegal supplement in the United States and the European Union.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Serious adverse effect',
    answer:
      'Any adverse effect that results in any life-threatening situation, inpatient hospitalization, persistent incapacity of a person’s ability to conduct a normal life, a congenital anomaly, reproductive harm, or death.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Hormone precursor',
    answer: 'A hormone used to create another hormone or hormone-like agent.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 10',
    topic: 'Supplementation',
    question: 'Gynecomastia',
    answer: 'A condition in males characterized by breast tissue growth.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Health risk assessment (HRA)',
    answer:
      'A screening tool used to evaluate the benefits and the risks associated with starting any type of exercise that is strenuous in nature.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Contraindication',
    answer:
      'A specific situation where a medication, procedure, or exercise should be avoided because it may prove to be harmful to the individual.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Physical Activity Readiness Questionnaire (PAR-Q+)',
    answer:
      'A detailed questionnaire designed to assess an individual’s physical readiness to engage in structured exercise.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'False-positive screenings',
    answer:
      'A screening where the results of the health risk assessment might indicate a need for medical clearance, when one is in fact not needed.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Health history questionnaire (HHQ)',
    answer:
      'A questionnaire with lists of questions that pertain to health history and habits, such as exercise history, eating behaviors, and general lifestyle.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Thermoregulation',
    answer:
      'The physiological process by which the body maintains a relatively constant internal body temperature, including events like sweating to cool the body and shivering to warm the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Peripheral vasodilation',
    answer:
      'The action of expanding the diameter of a blood vessel near the surface of the skin, which helps remove heat from the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Diastolic blood pressure (DBP)',
    answer:
      'The pressure in arteries and other blood vessels when heart is at rest or between beats; the second (bottom) number recorded.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Arterial system',
    answer: 'The system of arteries carrying blood away from the heart.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Brachial artery',
    answer:
      'The primary artery of the upper arm, which is often used as a site for measuring blood pressure.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Anthropometry',
    answer:
      'The field of study of the measurement of living humans for purposes of understanding human physical variation in size, weight, and proportion.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Body mass index (BMI)',
    answer:
      'The measurement of a person’s weight relative to his or her height, which is used to estimate the risks of obesity.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Circumference measurement',
    answer:
      'The measurement that determines the overall dimension (girth) of a body segment, which can be used to estimate body composition or the prevalence of obesity.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Waist circumference',
    answer:
      'A measurement that represents the narrowest circumference taken around the midline of the body at the approximate height of the umbilicus (belly button).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Waist-to-hip ratio (WHR)',
    answer:
      'The relative score expressing the ratio of the waist circumference to the hip circumference, which correlates to the risk for developing cardiovascular disease.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Gluteal fold',
    answer:
      'The area where the fold of the buttocks joins the back of the thigh.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Skinfold measurements',
    answer:
      'A technique used to estimate body fat in which calipers are used to pinch the skin in certain areas of the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Jackson and Pollock 7-Site protocol',
    answer:
      'Measures the thickness of skinfolds at seven different places within the body to estimate body fat percentage.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Jackson and Pollock 3-Site protocol',
    answer:
      'Measures the thickness of skinfolds at three different places within the body to estimate body fat percentage.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Four-site Durnin– Womersley protocol',
    answer:
      'Measures the thickness of skinfolds at four different places (biceps, triceps, subscapular, and suprailiac) within the body to estimate body fat percentage.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA)',
    answer:
      'A body composition assessment technique that estimates body fat percentage by measuring the resistance to the flow of electrical currents introduced into the body.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Archimedes’ principle',
    answer:
      'The assumption stating that the volume of fluid displaced is equivalent to the volume of an object fully immersed in that fluid or to the specific fraction of the volume below the surface.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Cardiorespiratory ﬁtness',
    answer:
      'The ability of the circulatory and respiratory systems to provide the body with oxygen during activity.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Cardiorespiratory assessments',
    answer:
      'Protocols intended to measure the aerobic fitness of an individual.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'YMCA 3-minute step test',
    answer:
      'An aerobic test that measures the cardiovascular fitness of an individual based on a 3-minute bout of stair-stepping at a specific cadence.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Recovery heart rate (RHR)',
    answer:
      'The number of heartbeats measured after exercise ceases, which provides some indication of an individual’s fitness level (i.e., more conditioned people recover more rapidly).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Rockport walk test',
    answer:
      'An aerobic test for deconditioned individuals or those of low fitness levels in which they are instructed to walk as fast as possible and have their pulse taken immediately after completing 1 mile.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: '1.5-mile (2.4 km) run test',
    answer:
      'An aerobic test that measures cardiorespiratory endurance by having the participant cover the distance of 1.5 miles in as short a time as possible.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Talk test',
    answer:
      'An aerobic test that measures the participant’s ability to talk or hold a conversation during an activity at various intensity levels.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Steady-state (SS) heart rate',
    answer:
      'Any stage at which the physiological response of heart rate from the cardiovascular system becomes relatively constant in relation to the amount of work being performed (i.e., the heart rate response matches the level of work being performed).',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 11',
    topic: 'Health, Wellness, and Fitness Assessments',
    question: 'Anaerobic energy systems',
    answer:
      'Energy systems used to perform work in which glycogen is converted to glucose and oxygen is insufficient to break down pyruvate and create adenosine triphosphate.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Overhead squat assessment  (OHSA)',
    answer:
      'A movement assessment designed to assess dynamic posture, core stability, and neuromuscular control of the whole body during a squatting motion.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Single-leg squat assessment',
    answer:
      'A movement assessment that assesses dynamic posture, lower-extremity strength, balance, and overall coordination in a single-limb stance.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Pushing assessment',
    answer:
      'An assessment that challenges the upper extremities and trunk during a pushing movement to identify movement impairments and potential muscle imbalances.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Pulling assessment',
    answer:
      'An assessment that challenges the upper extremities and trunk during a pulling movement to identify movement impairments and potential muscle imbalances.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Push-up test',
    answer:
      'A performance assessment that measures muscular endurance of the upper extremities during a pushing movement.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Bench press strength assessment',
    answer:
      'A performance assessment designed to estimate the one-repetition maximum of the bench press exercise.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Squat strength assessment',
    answer:
      'A performance assessment designed to estimate the one-repetition maximum of the squat exercise.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Vertical jump assessment',
    answer:
      'A performance assessment designed to test maximal jump height and lower extremity power.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Long jump assessment',
    answer:
      'A performance assessment designed to test maximal jump distance and lower extremity power.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: '40-yard dash assessment',
    answer:
      'A performance assessment designed to test reaction capabilities, acceleration, and maximal speed.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Lower extremity functional test (LEFT)',
    answer:
      'A performance assessment designed to test lateral speed and agility.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Pro shuttle (5-10-5) assessment',
    answer:
      'A performance assessment designed to test lateral acceleration, deceleration, agility, and control.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Prone',
    answer: 'Lying facedown.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
  {
    source: 'NASM Personal Fitness Training: Chapter 12',
    topic: 'Posture, Movement, and Performance Assessments ',
    question: 'Supine',
    answer: 'Lying faceup.',
    type: 'Vocab',
    cert: 'NASM CPT',
  },
]
